[ eerie music ]
[ choral voices singing ]
[ male vocalist singing ]
[ male vocalist , choir singing ]
[ music , singing continue ]
[ female vocalist , choir singing ]
[ hinges squeaking ]
[ man counting in Russian ]
[ truck beeping ]
[ car horn honks ]
[ man shouts indistinctly ]
[ inquisitive music ]
[ man 2 ] We 're here . [ continues indistinctly ]
[ grunts ]
- [ bright music ] - [ indistinct chattering ]
- [ whirring ] - [ woman chuckles ]
[ sighs ]
[ inquisitive music ]
[ door creaks ]
[ female vocalist singing ]
[ clattering ]
- Hello ?
Who 's there ?
[ yowling ]
[ gasps ]
[ panting ]
- [ cat howls ] - [ screams ]
- You scared me to death , you mangy thing !
I 'm just lookin ' for an old well .
Know it ?
Not talkin ' , huh ?
Magic dowser , magic dowser .
Show me the well !
[ air horn blares ]
- [ gasps ] - [ thunder rumbles ]
[ screams ] Get away from me !
[ thunder crackles ]
- Ooh , let me guess . You 're from Texas or Utah .
Someplace dried out and barren , right ?
I heard about water-witching before .
But it doesn 't make sense .
I mean , it 's just an ordinary branch .
- It 's a dowsing rod !
- Ow !
- And I don 't like being stalked !
Not by psycho nerds or their cats !
- He 's not really my cat . He 's kind of feral .
You know , wild ?
Of course , I do feed him every night .
And sometimes he 'll come to my window
and bring me little dead things .
- Look , I 'm from Pontiac .
- Huh ? - Michigan ?
And if I 'm a water witch , then where 's the secret well ?
- You stomp too hard , and you 'll fall in it .
- Oh !
- See ? - [ thumping echoes ]
It 's supposed to be so deep ,
if you fell to the bottom and looked up ,
you 'd see a sky full of stars in the middle of the day .
- Huh .
- Surprised she let you move in .
My grandma ? She owns the Pink Palace .
Won 't rent to people with kids .
- What do you mean ?
- Oh , I 'm not supposed to talk about it .
I 'm Wybie . Wybie Lovat .
- " Wybie " ? - Short for " Wyborne . "
Not my idea , of course .
What 'd you get saddled with ?
- I wasn 't " saddled " with anything .
It 's Coraline . - Caroline what ?
- Coraline . Coraline Jones .
- Hmm . It 's not real scientific ,
but I heard an ordinary name like Caroline
can lead people to have ordinary expectations about a person .
- [ grumbles ] - Wyborne ?
- I think I heard someone calling you , Wyborne .
- What ? I didn 't hear anything .
- Oh , I definitely heard someone , " Why-were-you-borne . "
- Wyborne ! - [ bell ringing ]
- Grandma !
[ chuckles ]
- Well , great to meet a Michigan water witch .
But I 'd wear gloves next time .
- Why ?
- ' Cause that dowsing rod of yours , it 's poison oak .
[ gasps ]
[ blows raspberry ]
[ faint splash ]
- I almost fell down a well yesterday , Mom .
- Uh-huh .
- I would have died .
- That 's nice .
- Hmm . So can I go out ?
I think it 's perfect weather for gardening .
- No , Coraline . Rain makes mud .
Mud makes a mess .
- Mom , I want stuff growing when my friends come to visit .
Isn 't that why we moved here ?
- Something like that .
But then we had the accident .
- It wasn 't my fault you hit that truck !
- I never said it was .
- I can 't believe it .
You and Dad get paid to write about plants
and you hate dirt .
- Coraline , I don 't have time for you right now .
And you still have unpacking to do .
Lots of unpacking !
- That sounds exciting .
- Oh , some kid left this on the front porch .
- [ Wybie 's voice ] " Hey , Jonesy .
Look what I found in Grandma 's trunk .
Look familiar ? Wybie . "
[ groans ]
- Huh .
A little me ? That 's weird .
- What 's his name anyway ?
- Wybie . I 'm way too old for dolls .
Hey , Dad . How 's the writing going ?
Dad !
- Hello , Coraline .
And Coraline ... doll ?
- Do you know where the garden tools are ?
- It 's pouring out there , isn 't it ?
- Hmm . It 's just raining .
- Hmm , what 'd " the boss " say ?
- " Don 't even think about going out , Coraline Jones ! "
- Then you won 't need the tools .
- Oh ...
[ door squeaks ]
- Oh !
You know , this house is 150 years old .
- So ? - So explore it .
Go out and count all the doors and windows
and write that down , or list everything that 's blue .
Just let me work !
- [ sighs ] - [ keyboard clicking ]
- Ugh !
Agh !
Oh , ugh !
[ squeaks ]
Ah !
[ door squeaks ]
[ crackling ]
- No . No , no ! No !
[ screams ]
- One boring blue boy
in a painfully boring painting .
Four incredibly boring windows .
And no more doors .
All right , little me . Where are you hiding ?
Huh ?
Hey , Mom ! Where does this door go ?
- I 'm really , really busy !
- I think it 's locked !
Please ? - [ groans ]
- Will you stop pestering me if I do this for you ?
[ whimpers ]
- Fine !
[ ripping ]
- Bricks ? I don 't get it !
- They must have closed this off
when they divided up the house .
- You 're kidding . And why is the door so small ?
- We made a deal .
Zip it !
- You didn 't lock it . - [ mother yells ]
♪ - Oh , my twitchy , ♪ ♪ witchy girl ♪
♪ I think you are so nice ♪
♪ I give you bowls of porridge ♪
♪ And I give you bowls of ice ... cream ♪
- Why don 't you ever cook , Mom ?
- Coraline , we 've been through this before .
Your dad cooks , I clean ,
and you stay out of the way .
I swear , I 'll go food shopping soon as we finish the catalog .
Try some of the chard . You need a vegetable .
- It looks more like slime to me .
- Well , it 's slime or bedtime , fusspot .
Now what 's it gonna be ?
- Think they 're trying to poison me ?
[ sighs ]
Don 't forget about me , guys , okay ?
Good night , little me .
[ door squeaks ]
[ mouse squeaks ]
[ squeaking ]
[ squeaks ]
[ Coraline gasps ]
Whoa .
- Huh ? - [ crickets chirping ]
[ woman humming ]
[ sniffing ]
- Hmm , something smells good .
[ humming ]
- Mom ?
What are you doin ' here in the middle of the night ?
- You 're just in time for supper , dear .
- You 're not my mother .
My mother doesn 't have bu - - but - -
- Bu - - b-buttons ?
[ laughs ] Do you like them ?
I 'm your Other Mother , silly .
Now go tell your Other Father that supper 's ready .
Well , go on . He 's in his study .
- [ keys pinging ] - Hello ?
- Hello , Coraline .
Wanna hear my new song ?
- My father can 't play piano . - No need to .
This piano plays me .
Look .
[ music playing ]
- Makin ' up a song about Coraline J
♪ She 's a peach , she 's a doll ♪
♪ She 's a pal of mine ♪
♪ She 's as cute as a button ♪ ♪ in the eyes of everyone ♪
♪ Whoever laid their eyes on Coraline ♪
♪ When she comes around exploring ♪
♪ Mom and I will never ♪ ♪ ever make it boring ♪
♪ Our eyes will be on Coraline ♪
- I 'm - - sorry , but
she said to tell you the food 's ready .
- Mmm .
Who 's starvin ' ? Raise your hand .
Whoa ! - [ laughs ]
- [ Dad ] Ahem .
We give our thanks and ask to bless
our mother 's golden chicken breast .
[ laughs ]
[ bell jingles ]
- Mmm .
This chicken is good !
- Hungry , aren 't you ?
- Do you have any gravy ?
- Well , here comes the gravy train .
Choo-choo !
[ chuckles ]
- Huh .
- Another roll ? Sweet peas ?
Corn on the cob ?
- I 'm real thirsty .
- Of course . Any requests ?
- Mango milkshake ?
[ gulps ]
" Home " ?
- We 've been waiting for you , Coraline .
- For me ? - [ Dad ] Yep .
It wasn 't the same here without you , kiddo .
- I didn 't know I had another mother .
- Of course , you do . Everyone does .
- Really ? - Uh-huh .
And soon as you 're through eating ,
I thought we 'd play a game .
[ tapping ]
- You mean , like hide and seek ?
- Perfect ! Hide and seek in the rain .
- What rain ?
- [ thunder crackles ] - Huh !
What about the mud ?
- We love mud here .
- Mud facials , mud baths , mud pies .
It 's great for poison oak .
- How 'd you know [ - - ?
I 'd love to play ,
but I 'd better get home to my other mother .
- But I 'm your Other Mother .
- I mean my other other mother .
Mom Number One ?
- Hoo-hoo ! - I think I should get to bed .
- Of course , sweetheart . It 's all made up .
- But - - - Come along , sleepyhead .
- [ gasps ] Wow .
- Hello , Coraline ! - Hello !
- What 's shakin ' , baby ?
- Hello . - [ faint snapping ]
- Hey , how 's it goin ' , Loper ?
- Where 's your swampers and toque ?
- Cripes almighty ! How are my best trolls ?
I can 't wait till summer . You 're both comin ' , right ?
- We 're already here , Coraline . - Gone to Oregon ?
- Oh .
The mud .
[ yawns ]
[ switch clicks ]
- See you soon . - See you soon .
[ yawns ]
[ faint dripping ]
- [ gasps ] It 's gone !
My poison oak ! It 's gone !
Huh .
[ shrill whistling ]
- It was incredibly real , Mom .
Only you weren 't really you . You were my Other Mother .
- Buttons for eyes , huh ?
Coraline , you only dreamed you ate all that chicken .
Take your multivitamin , at least .
- You were in the dream too , Dad .
You had wild-looking pajamas and orange monkey slippers .
- [ chuckles ] Orange ?
My monkey slippers are blue .
Psst . Can you get me
some of that magic mud you were talking about ?
Because I have a terrible case of writers ' rash on my ...
- Ahem !
- If the real Charlie Jones wants his pages edited ,
he 'd better wrap them up ASAP .
Coraline , why don 't you go visit downstairs ?
I bet those actresses would love to hear your dreams .
- Miss Spink and Forcible ?
But you said they 're dingbats !
- Mm-hmm .
- Bobinsky , Bobinsky , Bobinsky .
[ sniffs ]
Ugh ! Poo-wee !
[ knocking on door ]
- Hello ?
I think our mail got mixed up !
Shall I leave it outside or - -
[ gasps ]
[ clucking ]
- Hmm .
- Secret !
[ gasps ]
- Famous jumping mouse circus not ready ...
[ chomps ] ... little girl .
- Circus ?
Oh , I brought this for you .
[ sniffs ]
Mmm .
[ speaking Russian ]
- Huh ?
- New cheese samples ?
[ grunts ]
[ crackling ]
Very clever , using this mix-up
to sneak in my home and peek at mooshkas .
- " Mooshkas " ? - The mice !
- Oh , sorry .
I 'm Coraline Jones .
- And I am the Amazing Bobinsky .
But you call me Mr. B.
Because amazing , I already know that I am .
- Wha ... ?
- Ha ! You see , Caroline ?
The problem is my new songs go " Oompah , oompah . "
But the jumping mice play only " Toodle-toot , " like that .
It 's nice , but not so much amazing .
So now I switch to stronger cheese ,
and soon ... watch out !
Here , have beet . Make you strong .
Do svidaniya , Caroline .
- Cor-aline .
" Oompah-oompah . "
" Toodle-toot . Toodle-toot - - "
- Hey , Caroline !
[ speaking Russian ]
- Wait ! - No !
- Hmm .
The mice asked me to give you message .
- The jumping mice ?
- They are saying ,
" Do not go through little door . "
[ gasps ]
Do you know such a thing ?
- The one behind the wallpaper ?
But it 's all bricked up .
- Bah . So sorry . Is nothing .
Sometimes the mice are a little mixed up , hmm ?
They even get your name wrong , you know ?
They call you " Coraline " instead of " Caroline . "
Not Caroline at all !
Maybe I work them too hard .
[ shape ]
[ knocking ]
- [ barking ] - [ gasps ]
- Oh , cease your infernal yapping !
Oh , how nice to see you , Caroline .
Would you like to come in ?
We 're playing cards .
- Still Coraline , Miss Spink .
- Miriam ! Put the kettle on !
- April , I think you 're being followed !
- It 's the new neighbor , Miriam .
Caroline .
She 'll be having the oolong tea .
- Oh , no , no , no . I 'm sure she 'd prefer jasmine .
- No , oolong .
- Ah , jasmine it is , then .
[ sighs ]
- Come on , boys !
- Are those dogs real ?
- Our sweet departed angels .
Couldn 't bear to part with them .
So we had them stuffed .
Now there 's Hamish the Third ...
- Oh , go on . Have one .
It 's hand-pulled taffy from Brighton .
Best in the world .
- ... the Third , the Ninth ?
Yes , the Fourth , I 'm right - -
And Jock Jr . Jock Sr. ,
Jock the Third , the Fourth - -
Oh , and that 's Jock 's cousin twice removed .
I 'll read them if you like .
- Read what ?
- Oh , your tea leaves , dear .
They 'll tell me your future .
Drink up , then . Go on .
No , not all of it , not all of it .
That 's right . Now hand it over .
Oh ...
oh , Caroline .
Caroline , Caroline , Caroline .
You are in terrible danger .
- Oh , give me that cup , April .
Your eyes are going .
- My eyes ? You 're blind as a bat !
- Oh , now . Well , not to worry , child .
It 's good news .
There 's a tall handsome beast in your future .
- A what ?
- Miriam , really . You 're holding it wrong .
See ? Danger .
- What do you see ?
- I see a very peculiar hand .
- I see a giraffe .
- Giraffes don 't just fall from the sky , Miriam !
- [ crashes ] - Oh , Lord !
- Well , what should I do ?
- Never wear green in your dressing room .
- Acquire a very tall stepladder .
And be very , very careful .
Oh !
Now was there something you came to tell us ?
- No . I guess not . Thanks for the tea , though .
- [ Miriam ] Toodle-oo . - [ April ] Cheery-bye .
Do you have any nice Queens for Mummy ?
[ dog whimpers ]
- Danger ?
[ clicks ]
- Oh !
- Great ! The village stalker !
- Ow ! I wasn 't stalking you .
We 're hunting banana slugs .
- What do you mean , we ?
[ cat meows ]
- Ha ! Your cat 's not wild ! He 's a wuss puss !
- What ?
He hates to get his feet wet . Jeez !
- Wuss puss .
So that doll , did you make it look like me ?
- Oh , no !
I found it that way .
It 's older than Grandma .
Old as this house , probably .
- Come on . Blue hair ,
my swampers and raincoat ?
- Hey ! Check out " Slugzilla ! "
- You 're just like them .
- Huh ?
- I meant my parents .
They don 't listen to me either .
- Mm-hmm . Do you mind ?
Nom , nom ... [ moans ]
[ screams ]
Hmm ... - Ew !
[ laughs ]
- You know , I 've never been inside the Pink Palace .
- You 're kidding .
- Grandma 'd kill me .
Thinks it 's dangerous or something .
- Dangerous ?
- Well , she had a twin sister .
- So ?
- When they were kids , Grandma 's sister disappeared .
She says she was stolen .
- Stolen ? - [ meows ]
Well , what do you think ?
- Uh , I don 't know . Maybe she just ran away .
- Wyborne ! - [ bell ringing ]
- Look , I gotta go . - Wait a minute !
Hmm .
[ mouse squeaks ]
[ squeaks ]
[ squeaking ]
[ Other Mother humming ]
- Welcome back , darling .
- Hi .
- So thoughtful of you to send this nice cheddar , Coraline .
- Cheddar ?
Oh ! The mice bait .
- Would you go fetch your father ?
I bet he 's hungry as a pumpkin by now .
- You mean , my Other Father ?
- Your better father , dear . He 's out in the garden .
- But my parents don 't have time to garden .
- Shh ! Shh !
- Mmm .
- Go on .
[ gasps ]
Oh ! - [ croaks ]
- [ laughs ]
- Hey !
- I love your garden !
- Our garden , Coraline .
- [ giggles ] Stop tickling me !
- Oh , daughter in distress .
[ tooting ]
- Tickle no more , you dragonsnappers .
- Well , she said it 's time for dinner .
Breakfast ? Food ?
- Hop on , kiddo . I wanna show you something .
- I can 't believe you did this !
- Mother said you 'd like it .
For she knows you like the back of her hand .
- Mmm , so good .
- I love dinner breakfast food .
- Coraline , Mr. Bobinsky has invited you
to come see the jumping mice perform after dinner .
- Really ? That know-it-all Wybie said
it was all in Mr. B 's head . I knew he was wrong .
- Well , everything 's right in this world , kiddo .
- Your father and I will clean up
while you and your " friend " " head upstairs .
- My friend ?
Great . Another Wybie .
Hello , " Why-were-you-borne . "
Hello ?
- I thought you 'd like him more if he spoke a little less .
So I fixed him .
- So he can 't talk at all ?
- Nope . - Hmm .
I like it .
- Now run along , you two , and have fun .
- You 're awful cheerful ,
considering you can 't say anything .
Um , it didn 't hurt , did it , when she ...
[ chuckles ]
[ knocks ]
- Whoa !
- [ clucks ] - Cool !
[ laughs ]
[ pops ]
[ clucking ]
[ popping ]
- Look at you ! [ laughs ]
- [ Mr. B ] Lady and gentleman !
For to tickle your eyes and ears
and making hearts to thump ,
I , Sergei Alexander Bobinsky ,
am introducing my astoun-dishing ,
stupen-dulous and amazing
Jumping Mouse Circus !
[ squeaking ]
- My name !
[ music playing ]
- It 's wonderful , Wybie !
[ music continues ]
- [ music stops ] - Wow !
- [ music resumes ] - [ mice squeaking ]
- Yeah ! Whoo ! That was great !
- Very , very thank you , lady and gentleman .
[ squeaks ]
[ music resumes ]
[ applause ]
- We loved it , Mr. B. It was so , so ...
- Ah ...
- Amazing !
- You are very welcome any time you like .
You and also your good friend there .
Do svidaniya , Coraline .
[ yawns ]
[ groans ]
[ grunts ]
- There were garden squash like balloon animals
and snapdragons .
Oh , and upstairs I saw a real mouse circus .
Not pretend like the crazy man 's in our house .
- You sure you won 't come ?
- Don 't fret , Charlie . They 'll love the new catalog .
At least they 'll love my chapters .
I did not call him crazy , Coraline .
He 's drunk .
- Well , I guess I 'll see you around , you dizzy dreamer .
- Dad ! I 'm not five anymore !
[ car gears grinding ]
- [ music playing ] - Ah !
[ recorded music playing ]
- My kingdom for a horse !
[ crashes ]
- Put them back .
- But , Mom , the whole school 's gonna wear boring gray clothes .
No one will have these .
- Put them back .
- My Other Mother would get them .
- Maybe she should buy all your clothes .
- Coraline ] So what do you think 's in the other apartment ?
- I don 't know .
Not a family of Jones imposters .
- Then why 'd you lock the door ?
- Oh , I found some rat crap .
And I thought you 'd feel safer .
- They 're jumping mice , Mom .
And the dreams aren 't dangerous .
They 're the most fun I 've had since we 've moved here .
- Your school might be fun .
- With those stupid uniforms ? Right .
- Had to give it a try .
How do you feel about a mustard , ketchup , salsa wrap for lunch ?
- Are you kidding me ?
- Hmm . Had to go food shopping anyway .
Dad 's planning something special .
- Disgusting !
- You wanna come along ?
You can pick out something you like .
- Oh , like the gloves ?
- [ sighs ] Look , Coraline ,
if things go well today , I promise I 'll make it up .
- That 's what you always say .
- Won 't be long .
- But / might be .
[ clicks ]
I knew it was real !
[ rain pattering ]
[ growls ]
- [ Other Mother 's voice ] " Dearest Coraline .
Miss Spink and Miss Forcible
have invited you downstairs after lunch .
I hope you like the new outfit I made you .
Love , Mother . "
[ crickets chirping ]
[ belches ]
[ cat meows ]
- Hmm . Wybie 's got a cat like you at home .
[ meows ]
Not the quiet Wybie , the one that talks too much .
You must be the Other Cat .
- No . I 'm not the other anything .
I 'm me .
- Um , I can see you don 't have button eyes .
But if you 're the same cat , how can you talk ?
- I just can .
- Cats don 't talk at home .
- No ? - Nope .
- Well , you 're clearly the expert on these things .
After all , I 'm just a big fat " wuss puss . "
- Come back , please ?
I 'm sorry I called you that . I really am .
How 'd you get here ?
- I 've been coming here for a while .
It 's a game we play .
She hates cats
and tries to keep me out . But she can 't , of course .
I come and go as I please .
- The Other Mother hates cats ?
- Not like any mother I 've ever known .
- What do you mean ? She 's amazing !
- You probably think this world is a dream come true .
But you 're wrong .
The Other Wybie told me so .
- That 's nonsense . He can 't talk .
- Perhaps not to you .
We cats , however , have far superior senses than humans ,
and can see and smell and - -
Shh - - I hear something right over ...
[ meows ]
[ violin whines ]
[ musical instruments tuning ]
[ dog sniffles ]
[ tuning continues ]
[ panting ]
- Hey , Wybie .
[ tuning fades ]
[ music playing ]
She 's practically naked !
♪ - I 'm known as the siren ♪ ♪ of all Seven Seas ♪
♪ The breaker of hearts by the bay ♪
♪ So if you go swimming ♪
♪ With bowlegged women ♪
♪ I might steal your weak heart away ♪
[ dogs barking ]
[ music continues ]
- Oh , my God .
♪ - A big-bottomed ♪ ♪ sea witch ♪
♪ May bob through the waves ♪
♪ And hope to lead sailors astray ♪
♪ But a true ocean goddess ♪ ♪ must fill out her bodice ♪
♪ To present an alluring display ♪
[ barking ]
- Oh !
♪ - Beware of old oysters ♪
♪ Too large in the chest ♪
♪ Let 's banish them from the buffet ♪
♪ I 'm far more nutritious - - ♪
♪ - You smell like ♪ ♪ the fishes ! ♪
♪ - Did I hear a banshee ? ♪ {
♪ - You 're sea green ♪ ♪ with envy ♪
♪ - This mermaid ♪ ♪ enchantress .. ♪
♪ - No , I , ♪ ♪ " Birth of Venus " .. ♪
♪ - Will send sailors ♪ ♪ swooning all day - - ♪
- Oh !
[ gasps ]
[ music stops ]
[ barking ]
[ pants ]
- I can 't look .
- Ready to break a leg , Miriam ?
- Our lives for the theater , April .
[ dogs barking ]
[ laughs ]
- " What a piece of work is man .
How noble in reason . "
- " How infinite in faculty .
In form and moving , how express and admirable . "
- " In action , like an angel . "
- " In apprehension , how like a god . "
[ screams ]
- " The beauty of the world . "
- [ laughs ]
- " The paragon of animals . "
- Yeah !
[ screams ]
[ laughs ]
[ barking ]
- Hey , there .
- Was it wonderful , dear ?
- Oh , yeah . They swooped down
and pulled me right out of my seat , Spink and Forcible .
Only they weren 't old ladies . That was just a disguise .
But then I was flying through the air .
And it was ...
Oh , it was magic .
- You do like it here , don 't you , Coraline ?
- Uh-huh .
Good night , Wybie .
- You could stay here forever , if you want to .
- Really ?
- Sure . We 'll sing and play games .
And Mother will cook your favorite meals .
- There 's one tiny little thing we need to do .
- What 's that ?
- Well , it 's a surprise .
- For you , our little doll .
Black is traditional .
But if you 'd prefer pink or vermillion or chartreuse .
- [ gasps ]
- Though you might make me jealous .
- No way !
You 're not sewing buttons in my eyes !
- Oh , but we need a yes if you want to stay here .
- So sharp , you won 't feel a thi - - ow !
- There now , it 's your decision , darling .
We only want what 's best for you .
- I 'm going to bed right now !
- Bed ? - Before dinner ?
- I 'm really , really tired , yeah .
[ yawns ]
I just need to sleep on things .
- Well , of course you do , darling .
I 'll be happy to tuck you in .
- Oh , no thanks . You 've done so much already .
- You 're welcome .
And I - -
We aren 't worried at all , darling .
Soon you 'll see things our way .
- What 's wrong , Coraline ?
Don 't you wanna play ?
- Yeah . I wanna hug your face .
- Get a grip , soldier !
- Hey , where 's your buttons , Loper ?
- You wanna stay , don 't you ?
- Going home tonight , robots .
And I won 't ... be ... back .
- Go to sleep , go to sleep .
- [ Other Mother 's voice ] Little thing we need to do .
- [ Other Father 's voice ] So sharp , you won 't
feel a thing .
- Go to sleep , go to sleep .
- Soon you 'll see things our way .
- Mom ! Dad !
[ gasps ] Oh , God .
I 'm still here ?
[ rattles ]
[ piano playing ]
[ banging keys ]
- Hey , you ! Where 's the Other Mother ?
- I wanna go home ! - [ bangs ]
All will be swell soon as Mother 's refreshed .
Her strength is our strength .
Mustn 't talk when Mother 's not here .
- If you won 't even talk to me , I 'm gonna find the Other Wybie .
He 'll help me . - No point .
He pulled a long face .
And Mother didn 't like it .
- Oh !
[ crickets chirping ]
[ cat meows ]
And what do you think you 're doing ?
- Well , I 'm getting out of here .
That 's what I 'm doing .
Huh ? Something 's wrong .
Shouldn 't the old well be here ?
- Nothing out here .
It 's the empty part of this world .
She only made what she knew would impress you .
- But why ?
Why does she want me ?
- She wants something to love , I think .
Something that isn 't her .
Or maybe she just loves something to eat .
- Eat ?
That 's ridiculous . Mothers don 't eat daughters .
- I don 't know . How do you taste ?
[ chuckles ]
- Huh ?
But how can you walk away from something
and still come back to it ?
- Walk around the world .
- Small world .
- [ distant fanfare plays ] - Hang on !
[ squeaks ]
- Stop ! He 's one of the circus mice !
- [ squeaks ] - [ crunches ]
[ gasps ]
- I don 't like rats at the best of times .
But this one was sounding an alarm .
- Good Kitty .
- They say even the proudest spirit can be broken ...
with love .
[ gasps ]
- Of course , chocolate never hurts .
Like one ?
They 're cocoa beetles from Zanzibar .
- Ugh !
I want to be
with my real mom and dad !
I want you to let me go !
- Is that any way to talk to your mother ?
- You aren 't my mother .
- Apologize at once , Coraline !
- No !
- I 'll give you to the count of three .
One ...
two ...
[ yells ] three !
- Ow ! What are you doing ?
Ow , that hurts !
- You may come out when you 've learned to be a loving daughter !
- [ shouts ]
[ panting ]
[ gasps ]
Who 's there ?
- Hush and shush .
For the Beldam might be listening .
- You ...
you mean , the Other Mother ?
Who are you ?
- Don 't remember our names .
But I remember my true mommy .
- Why are you all here ?
- The Beldam .
- She spied on our lives through the little doll 's eyes .
- And saw that we weren 't happy .
- So she lured us away with treasures and treats ...
- And games to play .
- Gave all that we asked
- Yet we still wanted more .
- So we let her sew the buttons .
- She said that she loved us .
But she locked us here ...
- [ all ] And ate up our lives .
- Well , she can 't keep me in the dark forever .
Not if she wants to win my life .
Beating her is my only chance .
- Perhaps if you do win your escape ,
you could find our eyes .
- Has she taken those too ?
- Yes , miss , and hidden them .
- Find our eyes , mistress ,
and our souls will be freed .
- I 'll try .
[ gasps ]
[ grunting ]
- Wybie ?
Did she do this to you ?
I hope that feels better . - Shh !
- [ Beldam ] Coraline ? Is that you ?
- Let 's go !
[ gasps ]
- Coraline ? - [ rattles ]
- Come on . She 'll hurt you again .
- Coraline ?
How dare you disobey your mother !
- [ gasps ]
- Coraline ?
[ panting ]
- [ yells ] I 'm home !
Anybody here ?
Hello ? Hello , hello ?
Real Dad ?
Real Mom ?
Oh , Mom 's groceries !
- [ buzzing ] - Oh , that 's disgusting .
[ doorbell rings ]
- I missed you guys so much !
You 'll never - -
Oh , the Wybie that talks .
- Huh ? [ chuckles ]
Yeah . So you know that old doll I gave you ?
Um , my grandma 's real mad .
Says it was her sister 's , the one that disappeared ?
- You stole that doll , didn 't you ?
- Well , it looked just like you .
And I figured ...
- It used to look like this pioneer girl .
Then Huck Finn , Jr .
Then it was this " Little Rascals " chick
with all these ribbons and braids !
Grandma 's missing sister !
I think I just met her . Come on .
- Listen , I 'm really not supposed to - - whoa !
- She 's in there .
- Can you unlock it ?
- Not in a million years . But it wouldn 't matter .
She can 't escape without her eyes .
None of the ghosts can .
- Uh ... yeah .
So I really need to get that doll .
- Great ! I 'd love to get rid of it .
Where are you hiding , you little monster ?
- You and Grandma been talkin ' ?
- The doll 's her spy !
It 's how she watches you .
Finds out what 's wrong with your life .
- The doll is my grandma 's spy ?
- No , the Other Mother .
She 's got this whole world where everything 's better .
The food , the garden , the neighbors .
But it 's all a trap .
- [ gulps ]
Yeah , I think I heard someone calling me , Jonesy .
- You don 't believe me ? You can ask the cat !
- The cat ?
I 'll just tell Grandma that you couldn 't find the doll .
Ow ! - You 're not listening to me !
- That 's ' cause you 're crazy !
[ screams ]
- You creep ! - Crazy !
- Crazy ?
You 're the jerk wad that gave me the doll !
Mom ? Dad ?
Pick it up , Dad , pick it up .
- Dad '
- I 'm digging in my garden right now .
But leave a message
and I 'll get right back to you .
- Where have you gone ?
[ faint whimper ]
Uh , don 't you only make wings for the dead ones ?
- Just looking ahead , dear .
Angus hasn 't been feeling very well of late .
- April ? Aren 't you getting ready ?
- We 've lost our ride , Miriam .
Caroline says her parents have vanished quite completely .
- What ?
We 've waited months for those tickets !
- I suppose we could walk .
- With your gammy legs ?
It 's nearly two miles to the theater !
Ahem !
- Oh , oh , yes . Your missing parents .
We know just what you need .
Miriam , get - - that 's right .
- How is 100-year-old candy gonna help ?
[ dogs whimper ]
[ screaming ]
[ rattling ]
- There you go , sweetie .
- What 's it for ?
- Well , it might help .
They 're good for bad things sometimes .
- No , they 're good for lost things .
- It 's bad things , Miriam .
- Lost things , April .
- Bad . - Lost .
- Bad things ! - Lost !
- Bad ! - Lost !
- Good night , Mom .
Good night , Dad .
[ sobbing ]
[ faint purring ]
- [ purring ] - Hello .
How did you get in ?
Do you know where Mom and Dad are ?
[ gasps ]
- Mom ? Dad ?
[ glass squeaking ]
[ gasps ]
[ grunting ]
[ crashing ]
[ meows ]
- How did this happen ?
[ gasps ]
Oh , she 's taken them !
They 're not coming back , are they ? Mom and Dad ?
Not on their own .
Only one thing to do .
[ clatters ]
- You know you 're walking right into her trap .
- I have to go back .
They are my parents .
- Challenge her then .
She may not play fair , but she won 't refuse .
She 's got a thing for games .
- Hmm .
Okay .
[ wind whistles ]
- Coraline ? - Mom ?
- Coraline ! You came back for us !
- Mom !
- Darling , why would you run away from me ?
- Oh !
[ chuckles ]
Where are my parents ?
- Gosh , I have no idea where your old parents are .
Perhaps they 've grown bored of you
and run away to France .
- They weren 't bored of me . You stole them !
- Now don 't be difficult , Coraline .
Have a seat , won 't you ?
[ Other Father mumbling ]
[ gasps ]
[ clapping ]
[ squeaking ]
- Why don 't you have your own key ?
- Only one key . - Shh !
The garden squash need tending ,
don 't you think , pumpkin ?
- Squish squash , pumpkin song .
[ squeaking echoes ]
- Mom ? Dad ?
[ glass squeaking ]
- Where 'd she hide you ?
- [ bell rings ] - [ Beldam ] Breakfast time !
[ humming ]
- [ thinking ] Be strong , Coraline .
♪ - La-la ♪
♪ La-la ♪
♪ La-la .. ♪ - Why don 't we play a game ?
I know you like them .
- Everybody likes games .
- Uh-huh .
- What kind of game would it be ?
- An exploring game . A finding things game .
- And what is it you 'd be finding , Coraline ?
- My real parents .
- Too easy .
- And the eyes of the ghost children .
- Huh . What if you don 't find them ?
- If I lose , I 'll stay here with you forever
and let you love me .
[ sighs ]
And I 'll let you sew buttons into my eyes .
- Hmm .
And if you somehow win this game ... ?
- Then you let me go . You let everyone go .
My real father and mother , the dead children .
Everyone you 've trapped here .
- Deal .
- Not till you give me a clue .
- Oh , right .
In each of three wonders I 've made just for you ,
a ghost eye is lost in plain sight .
- And for my parents ?
[ chuckles , taps ]
Fine . Don 't tell me .
- [ sighs ] - [ tapping continues ]
It 's a deal .
[ gasps ]
[ dripping ]
[ sighs ]
What does she mean , " wonders " ?
Hmm .
[ croaks ]
- Ugh !
[ shape ]
No !
[ yelps ]
[ grunts ]
[ pants ]
[ buzzing ]
- Stop !
[ buzzing fades ]
Why steal this ?
[ gasps ]
Wow !
That must be it !
- Sorry .
- [ screams ] - So sorry .
Mother making me .
Don 't wanna hurt you !
Take it !
[ moans ]
[ crackling ]
- Bless you , miss ! You found me !
But there 's two eyes still lost .
Don 't worry .
I 'm getting the hang of it .
♪ - I 'm known as the siren ♪ ♪ of all Seven Seas ♪
♪ The breaker of hearts by the bay ♪
♪ So if you go swimmin ' ♪
♪ With bowlegged women ♪
♪ I might steal your weak heart away ♪
[ rustling ]
- [ snarls ] - [ gasps ]
[ growls ]
[ switch bangs ]
- The pearl .
[ screams ]
- Thief ! Give it back !
- Give it back ! Thief !
- Thief ! - Give it back !
- Thief ! - Thief !
- Give it back ! - Thief !
- Give it back ! - Give it back !
- Thief ! - Give it back !
- Thief !
Thief !
- Stop ! Thief !
[ screaming ]
[ crackling ]
- Hurry on , girl ! Her web is unwinding !
- Oh , Wybie .
[ yells ] Evil witch !
I 'm not scared !
[ door creaks ]
- [ slurring ] Hello ... golubushka .
- I 'm Coraline .
- Is this what you 're looking for ?
- Uh-huh .
- You think winning game is good thing ?
[ bangs ]
You 'll just go home , and be bored and neglected .
Same as always .
Stay here with us .
We will listen to you and laugh with you .
If you stay here ,
you could have whatever you want ...
[ speaking Russian ] ... always .
- You don 't get it , do you ?
- I don 't understand .
- Of course , you don 't understand .
You 're just a copy she made of the real Mr. B.
- Not even that ...
[ distorted ] anymore .
- [ screeches ] - [ gasps ]
[ gasps ]
- [ popping ] - [ screams ]
No !
[ grunts ]
[ bangs ]
[ low rumbling ]
Oh , God , I 've lost the game .
I 've lost everything .
[ sobbing ]
- [ rumbling stops ] - [ cat meows ]
- I think I mentioned
that I don 't like rats at the best of times .
- I think you might have said something like that .
- It looked like you needed this one , however .
- Thank you .
[ crackling ]
I 'm heading inside .
I still have to find my parents .
[ rumbles , bangs ]
[ crackling ]
Come on ! Quickly !
[ bangs ]
[ crackling ]
[ cat growls ]
- So , you 're back .
And you brought vermin with you ?
- [ yowls ] - No . I - -
I brought a friend .
- You know I love you .
Mm ...
- You have a very funny way of showing it .
- So where are they - -
The ghost eyes ?
- Hold on .
We aren 't finished yet , are we ?
- No , I suppose not .
After all , you still need to find
your old parents , don 't you ?
Too bad you won 't have this .
[ chuckles ]
- Be clever , miss .
Even if you win , she 'll never let you go !
- I already know where you 've hidden them .
- Mmm .
Well , produce them .
- They 're behind that door .
- Oh , they are , are they ?
[ glass squeaking ]
- [ Cat ] There . - [ squeaking ]
- Mom ? Dad ?
[ coughing ]
- Go on ! Open it .
They 'll be there , all right .
- You 're wrong , Coraline .
They aren 't there .
Now you 're going to stay here forever .
- No ... I 'm ... not !
[ cat yowls ]
[ screams ]
[ grunts ]
- No !
You horrible cheating girl !
[ crackling ]
[ gasps ]
[ cackles ]
[ meows ]
[ screaming ]
- No !
Where are you ?
You selfish brat !
[ twangs ]
[ laughs ]
You dare disobey your mother ?
- Oh !
- [ snarls ]
Please shut !
[ screams ]
- [ clicks ] - [ bangs ]
[ Beldam screams ]
Don 't leave me ! Don 't leave me !
I 'll die without you !
- [ banging ]
- Ah !
[ panting ]
[ gasps ]
- [ drips ]
- Coraline , we 're home !
- Mom ? Dad ? I missed you so much !
- Missed us ?
Oh , no , you broke my favorite snow globe .
- I didn 't break it .
It must have broke when you escaped !
- And cut your knee .
- Coraline , I asked you to count all the windows ,
not put your knee through them .
- But ...
- Well , get yourself cleaned up . We 're going out tonight .
- We got a lot to celebrate .
- You 're talking about your garden catalog ?
- Of course . What else ?
- But look at the snow on your clothes .
- What 's gotten into you , Coraline ?
- [ Dad ] Oh ! Oh !
- [ chuckles ]
So gonna order the tulips ?
- What 's that ? - For the garden party ?
- I have no idea what you 're talking about .
- Dad !
So , Mom , invitations ?
Don 't forget the invitations .
- Even Bobinsky ?
- Mr. B 's not drunk , Mom .
He 's just eccentric .
- [ laughs ]
- Good night , Coraline .
[ door creaks ]
[ door closes ]
[ meows ]
- Oh , hello again .
You still mad ?
I 'm really sorry I threw you at her - -
The Other Mother .
It was all I could think of .
I think it 's time , don 't you ?
To set them free ?
- It 's a fine , fine thing you did for us , miss .
- Well , I 'm glad it 's finally over .
- It is over and done with ... for us .
- What about me ?
- You 're in terrible danger , girl !
- But how ? I locked the door !
- It 's the key , miss . There 's only one ,
and the Beldam will find it .
- ' Tain 't all bad , miss .
Thou art alive . Thou art still living .
[ gasps ]
- I gotta hide this somewhere .
Somewhere she can never - -
[ meows ]
- Out of my way !
[ door creaks ]
[ creaking ]
- " Oh , my twitchy witchy girl ,
I think you are so nice .
I give you bowls of porridge ,
and I give you bowls of ice ... cream .
I give you lots of kisses ...
[ rattles ]
- ... and I give you lots of hugs .
But I never give you sandwiches
with grease and worms and mung ... beans . "
[ rattles ]
- [ screams ]
[ banging ]
- [ air horn blares ] - [ gasps ]
- Yah !
[ grunts ]
[ gasps ]
[ screams ]
Oh-hh !
Get off !
[ screams ]
- [ grunts ]
[ rips ]
- [ screams ]
[ panting ]
[ faint dripping ]
- [ grunting ]
[ water splashes ]
- I 'm really sorry I didn 't believe you
about all this evil stuff , Coraline .
- Why did you change your mind ?
- Well , Grandma showed me this picture ...
after I called you crazy .
It 's her and her sister before she disappeared .
- The sweet ghost girl .
- Wyborne ! Come home ! - [ bell ringing ]
- [ sighs ] Oh , man .
What am I gonna tell her ?
- Just bring her by the house tomorrow .
We can tell her together .
- We - - we can ?
- You know , I 'm glad you decided to stalk me .
[ giggles ]
- It wasn 't my idea .
- [ meows ]
- Thanks for helping me , Miss Spink , Miss Forcible .
- Oh , look , April , Pink Ladies !
- Actually , it 's just lemonade .
How 's Angus doing ?
- Oh , much better , dear .
But he can 't duck his wings forever .
- Here comes a burp . [ belches ]
- Charlie !
- Oh , excusez-moi , but that pizza was delicious .
- Cold drinks ? - Oh , yeah , great .
- You were right , Coraline . I really hate dirt !
But the tulips look nice .
- Thanks , Mom .
- [ Mr. B. muttering ] Nyet , nyet .
Da , da , that is possible - -
- Ahem !
How are the mooshkas , Mr. B ?
- They tell me that you are savior , Caroline .
And soon as they are ready ,
they wish to give special " thanks you " performance .
- Wyborne , I know where I 'm goin ' .
I grew up here .
- Welcome , Ms. Lovat !
- Oh , hello .
- I 'm Coraline Jones .
I 've got so much to tell you !
- [ Mom ] Here . - [ Dad ] Thanks .
- [ April ] Do you want to pop a little gin in it , dear ?
- [ Miriam ] Of course .
[ purrs ]
[ music plays ]
[ choral voices singing ]
[ instrumental music playing ]
[ male vocalist singing ]
[ male vocalist , choir singing ]
[ music fades ]